

+2347068166293 oribuyakudamilola@gmail.com 1, Zaria Street, Garki 2, Abuja

Curious research analyst and project manager with over 10 years experience spanning research, project planning, investment analysis, strategy development and project execution across diverse industries including construction, energy, finance and Information Technology. Assumed extensive research and project management roles in both large and small institutions. Represented my institutions in various international fora and held meticulous engagements with very senior local and international leaders in the construction and energy industries.

Damilola is currently responsible for research, consulting services, project, contract and client management on various infrastructure projects with combined target investments of about \$1b.

Education

- 1. UNIVERSITY OF GREENWICH, UK MSC. CONSTRUCTION MANAGEMENT & ECONOMICS, DISTINCTION, 2015
- 2. BOWEN UNIVERSITY, IWO BSC. (HON) ECONOMICS, 2009, SECOND-CLASS UPPER
- 3. BOWEN UNIVERSITY, IWO PRE-DEGREE PROGRAMME, 2005
- 4. CHRISLAND COLLEGE, IDIMU WEST AFRICAN SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE (WASSCE), 2004
- 5. FEDERAL GOVERNMENT COLLEGE, ODOGBOLU
- 6. INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL, UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS

Experience

2016-PRESENT: GASINVEST LIMITED, NIGERIA MANAGER, CONSULTING SERVICES

Responsible for research, client, project and contract management; investment screening and feasibility assessments of projects.

Involvement:

- Supporting Guest Lecturer on course development and presentation, marking scheme development, grading, and recording of scores for Graduate students at the Emerald Energy Institute for Petroleum and Energy Economics, Policy and Strategic Studies, University of Port Harcourt
- 2. Planning & Development of a \$50m Industrial Park in partnership with Delta State Government
- 3. Evaluated The Paris Agreement and relevant local environmental and industry laws, regulations and guidelines to situate GasInvest's proposal for extinguishing gas flares under the Nigerian Gas Flare Commercialisation Programme (NGFCP)

- 4. Carried out research work for Facility for Oil Sector Transparency and Reform (FOSTER) on "Tackling vested interests and issues of lack of transparency that impede growth of the gas value chain in Nigeria."
- 5. Pre-feasibility Study for Sourcing, Transporting, Liquefying, Evacuating and Shipping of Natural Gas from Niger Delta, Nigeria to Richards Bay, South Africa
- 6. Feasibility study on the deployment of a Floating Storage and Regasification Unit in Nigeria
- 7. Pre-feasibility study for development of an 11mmscf/d small-scale LNG Plant in Nigeria, including storage and market receiving terminals in Nigeria and Republic Du Benin
- 8. Gas Sourcing for a Brownfield Methanol, Gas and LNG Plants in Central Africa (4.5Tcf):
- 9. Development & Implementation of a Gas Contract Management Software for subsidiaries of Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation.

2016-PRESENT: GASHUB NIGERIA LIMITED, NIGERIA OPERATIONS MANAGER

I am responsible for developing GasHub's gas portfolio in Nigeria and West Africa; sourcing and proactively locking-down new gas supplies; obtaining adequate and flexible access to national and private pipeline networks; opening up new markets in third-party or own gas demand projects; negotiation of agreements including Gas Sale and Purchase Agreements and Gas Transportation Agreements; and aligning business activities with the Nigerian gas network code.

Project(s):

 Sourcing, Transportation and Physical Trading of 6mmscf/d piped natural gas from Niger Delta to Shell Nigeria Gas in the Ogun-Guangdong Free Trade Zone (OGFTZ) through the Escravos-Lagos Pipeline System

2015-16: BULL MOOSE DERIVATIVES, LONDON GAS FUTURES TRADER

Bull Moose is a City of London-based proprietary trading firm, focused on a diverse range of markets across futures, options and foreign exchange.

Responsibilities:

 Acquired detailed knowledge of global and particularly, the UK gas industry dynamics, particularly current/future demand and supply drivers and their effects on prices; Analysed developments in the supply envelopes and compared with developments in consumption hubs, then developed trading strategies and took trade positions based on potential impact of demand and supply dynamics on prices within short and medium term trading windows.

2014-15: TECHGRADE CONSULTING; ABUJA

INTERIM MANAGING DIRECTOR

Techgrade is Nigeria's foremost civil engineering professional training company.

Responsibilities:

1. Highest ranking individual responsible for overall company performance and success; also responsible for making all top-level management decisions.

Projects:

- 1. Consultancy on World Bank-Financed State Employment and Expenditure (SEEFOR) Project Across 4 Niger-Delta States.
 - a. Led business development, implementation, project monitoring and evaluation efforts including:
 - I. Development of project work schedule and activities based on training needs assessment
 - II. Jointly developed training modules and training calendar with subject matter experts
 - III. Developed budget and budget performance monitoring tools and processes
 - IV. sourcing, allocation and management of resources vis-a-vis activities
 - V. invitation, screening and negotiations with third party service provider
- 2. Deployment of 3D Modelling & 360 Degrees Photography Solutions for Construction Project Management at Federal Roads Maintenance Agency (FERMA)

2010-14 - SETRACO NIGERIA LIMITED; ABUJA

PROJECT ANALYST - FINANCE

Setraco is one of the largest construction companies in Nigeria, specializing in roads and bridges. With projects executed in over 20 states, Setraco is playing a key role in Nigeria's drive for infrastructure development.

Responsibilities:

Business Process Analysis & Modelling, Project Management, Client Management, ERP Software Development, Coaching & Influencing, Course Content Development, Technical Writing, and Research

Projects:

- 1. Deployment of Oracle JDE ERP Software Solutions
 - a. Trained, coached, and influenced staff and management to ensure mass software adoption in the HQ and branches nation-wide.
 - b. Produced Technical documents and relevant documentation
 - c. Presented reports and documents to colleagues and management

2009-10 - ACCESS BANK PLC; ABAKALIKI RELATIONSHIP OFFICER

- a. Managed relationships within territory
- b. Supported in providing sound activity management reports.

Conferences, Workshops, and Site Visits

NIGERIA

- 1. Economic Recovery and Growth Plan Focus Labs (2018) I Presented Kwale Industrial Park Project being developed by Delta State Government with support from GasInvest to Vice President Prof. Yemi Osibajo and 3 Ministers. I requested for specific interventions
- 2. ESIA Screening Workshop with Department of Petroleum Resources and ESIA Scoping Workshop with Federal Ministry of Environment (2019) Developed and delivered presentation to top officials of the DPR and Federal Ministry of Environment regarding an industrial park project. The presentation covered the project's objectives, masterplan, scope of developmental and operational activities, overview of technologies, schedule etc. The workshops provides the basis for the two government agencies to outline the nature and scope of the environmental assessments to be carried out.
- 3. Community Engagement Workshop (2019) I was a member of the project team that visited 5 host communities of a planned industrial park project in Delta State Nigeria. For each engagement meeting, I planned the events with advice from the executive committee members within each community, arranged with the Nigerian police for security requirements, and interfaced with top officials from the Governor's office.

UNITED KINGDOM:

- 1. EcoBuild; ExCeL Center, London (2014) EcoBuild is UK's biggest gathering held annually to promote the sustainable and design construction industry. In the 2014 edition, I engaged ideas with leading architects, designers, contractors, installers, engineers, developers and energy managers from the sustainable design and construction industry on solutions for improving the energy efficiency of buildings, use of waste to power buildings off grid etc.
- 2. King's Cross Regeneration Project Scheme (2015) Tour visits to King's Cross, a 67-acre of previously underused industrial heartland area in London being redeveloped to comprise 50 new buildings, 1,900 new home, 20 new street, 10 new public parks and squares, 26 acres of open space that were either refurbished or built brand new.

REPUBLIQUE DU BENIN (2016):

1. Part of a team of two who carried out technical site visits of the Cotonou Port, West African Gas Pipeline Metering Station, and the Maria Gleta Power Plant regarding a proposed LNG project in Republique du Benin. Regasified LNG was planned to be sent to a power plant in Benin and to the Nigerian domestic gas industry through WAGP on a 50-50 basis.

SOUTH AFRICA (2019):

 Carried out technical site visits of South Africa's foremost CNG filling station, CNG plant and other ancillary facilities including a gasoline-to-CNG conversion facility for vehicles and a CNG dispatch and logistics monitoring centre for fulfilling CNG deliveries to industries.

CHINA (2019):

- 1. Carried out factory tour of Kohler Bathroom Ltd and other ceramics and porcelain factories in Faku County in Shenyang, China to determine typical set-up of ceramics industries and energy requirements to appropriately plan the development of an industrial park in Nigeria
- 2. Carried out site tour of a petrochemicals industrial park in Nanjing China to determine typical set-up of chemical industries and energy requirements to appropriately plan the development of an industrial park in Nigeria

Papers/Articles

<u>Partnering and the Viability of Affordable Housing Projects in London: Determining a causation</u> (MSc Thesis)

Towards AI: Personal Budgeting, Self-Control and Global Inequality

Skills

Playing Talking Drum, Writing, Tutoring

References

Available on request